CHUKWUJEKWU ANTHONY OBIANO

8A Lukesland Avenue Penkhull, (ST4 5JN) Stoke-On-Trent UK
• Cell: 07368668209; +07494616178
anthony.obiano@gmail.com

Personal statement

I am a resilient and apt Electrical and Electronics Engineer, with many years' experience in Telecommunications and data center infrastructure deployment project and maintenance. An energetic and on-hands person, who goes the extra-mile to meet organizational goal. Also, an enterprising fellow with background in implementing Civil, Mechanical and Electrical Telecommunication Projects. Now I build/operate Power (AC and DC) and cooling infrastructures that support network elements, servers, MSC, BSC and BTS (2G,3G and 4G) sites for a multinational communication Network.

Specialties

Rectifier and Back-up installations, UPS, BMS-AKCP, Electrical wiring, Generator installation, air conditioners and HVAC, Electrical design for Telecoms (panels and DB), Supervision skills, Spontaneous response to Emergency call,

Key skills

- Ability to conduct technical site survey in greenfield site and live data centre for upgrade.
- Installation of Rectifier and UPS, PDF and backup batteries, live cutover of DC power from one source to another in a brownfield data Centre with no downtime.
- Battery drain test on live battery onload. Also use of battery testing
- Preparation of Budget and cost estimate for Energy maintenance and new installation
- Project Management
- Knowledge of CAT5, CAT6 and Optic fiber cabling.
- Supervision of deployment of GSM 2G, RAN, 3G and 4G LTE.
- Health and safety at site.
- Supervision skills of civil and mechanical work on Telecom project.
- Supervision and monitor of BMS-AKCP alarms.
- Technical report using (MS excel or MS PowerPoint).

Qualifications

- B.Eng. Electrical and Electronics Engineering
- Nigerian society of Engineer Member
- Council for the Regulations Engineering in Nigeria.
- Huawei Diploma
- Project Management training
- Authorized person high voltage person training.
- Schneider Data centre trainings
- Commissioning and startup

EMPLOYMENT

Job Title: Power/BSS Engineer
Organization: 9Mobile formerly Etisalat

Location: Lagos Nigeria From: July 2017 – Present

Function as National Energy Deployment Infrastructure Engineer

Duties

- Supervision of installation of ABB Transformer 33KV/415V 1.5MVA, Air cool Oretea 1.5MVA AVR, Feeder pillar and Isolation panel within the substation in 9mobile Data centre.
- Implementation of 9Mobile D.C Power plant design specification and standard with MTTR across the country BTS, BSCs and Data center sites.
- Power audit to ensure adequate capacity on all power infrastructures such as Generators,
 Transformers, ATS & GTS, Rectifiers, UPS and Batteries, and Cooling.) for prospective device upgrades at BSC and Data centre.
- Supervision of installation and Maintenance of 160kw Socomec rectifier, PDF with backup bank of 4000AH@48Vdc.
- Ensure weekly report gets to reporting line progress on all energy project within the network.
- Supervision of installation and commissioning of Parallel Socomec 200Kw UPS and APDU.
- Schedule for generator maintenance and PPM for other Data centre facility infrastructure.
- monitor BMS and AKCP alarms on report e-board.
- Develop requirement for new upgrade and maintenance during technical site survey.

Job Title: Power Engineer Organization: Etisalat Nigeria Location: Lagos Nigeria

From: July 2011 – July 2017

Function as Regional Energy Deployment Infrastructure Engineer.

- Performs Technical site surveys to develop installation design plans DC and AC and Cooling.
- Facilitate and Ensure 100% power availability at all network sites. Track power outages drive improvement in network availability and service quality. (Root Cause Analysis)
- Implementation/execution of all preventive and corrective maintenance activities, which include in-house teams and contractors.
- React to emergency faults and ensure that all faults are rectified promptly within contracted SLA
- Ensure regular audit of M&E installations, Power Systems (Transformer, Generator, Rectifier, Battery backup, UPS, HVAC) for BTSSitesBSC MGWand data centers.
- · Completes and submits reports covering all job activity
- Estimates labour, material, construction, and equipment costs

Job Title: Power and Facility Officer

Organization: Mobitel Nigeria Location: Lagos Nigeria

From: November 2010 – June 2011

- Review designed drawings, specifications for vendor, for network requirements.
- Implement electrical equipment installations in facilities such as UPS, Rectifier, Back-up batteries, Generators and transformers cum maintenance plan.
- Oversee all electrical and cooling design and implementation in switch station and all owned BTS sites.
- Raise request for new project and choose contractor from data base according to their strength.
- Interface with grid supply company on planned and emergency bases.
- Liaise with NOC on status of the power equipment on Mobitel network.
- Supervises contractors work, appraise and issue job completion certificate for payment processing by finance.
- Give immediate solution before vendors or contractor responses.
- Ensure maintenance plan for power equipment is implemented as timed.
- Troubleshoot faults on power circuitry, cooling and come up with root cause analysis report

Hobbies and Interests Reading, Football, and Playing Games References are available on request